Guide to the Alfred S. Coumbe Collection 1917-1924
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Alfred S. Coumbe Collection
1917-1924
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.libraries.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 725
Coumbe, Alfred S.
6 linear feet of shelf space 5 boxes
Collection of materials related to Alfred S. Coumbe of Spokane during his World War I service in the U.S. Navy. Includes diaries, a photograph album, loose photographs, artifacts (uniforms and other textile items), and a few miscellaneous items.
Alfred S. Coumbe served in the United States Navy during World War I. Biographical information for Coumbe was not readily available when the collection was processed.
This collection includes papers and artifacts related to Alfred S. Coumbe of Spokane during his World War I service in the U.S. Navy. It includes diaries, a photograph album, loose photographs, uniforms and other textile items, and a few miscellaneous items.
This collection is arranged in two series:
Series 1. Papers, 1919-1924
Series 2. Artifacts (textile items), circa 1917-1919
This collection is open and available for research use.
The WSU Libraries purchased this collection from dealer Charles Apfelbaum in 2008 (MS.2008.05).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Coumbe, Alfred S. -- Archives --Archives
United States -- Navy -- History -- World War, 1914-1918
Sailors -- United States -- Archives; Diaries -- Specimens; Military uniforms -- Specimens
Military
- Series 1. Papers, 1919-1924
  - Diaries, 1917-1919 (Box 1)
  - Photograph album, 1919 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous items, 1919-1924 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, including images of the USS Bridgeport (1919), and the first anniversary ball for the crew of the USS Rochester, (1918), 1918-1919 (Box Oversize (folder))
- Series 2. Artifacts (textile items), circa 1917-1919
  - Naval uniform items: wool pants (2), wool tunic (Box 2)
  - Naval uniform items: cotton tunic, drawers, silk tie, silk scarf (Box 3)
  - Naval uniform items: spats/leggings. Also felt mat with American flag, and American Legion cap (Box 4)
  - Naval uniform items: cotton tunic with blue collar and cuffs, white cotton pants (Box 5)